thetechhacker.com 2019-07-14

# Privacy Policy

At Thetechhacker, accessible from [thetechhacker.com](https://thetechhacker.com/), one of our main priorities is the privacy of our visitors. This Privacy Policy document contains types of information that is collected and recorded by Thetechhacker and how we use it.

If you have additional questions or require more information about our Privacy Policy, do not hesitate to contact us through email at pr@thetechhacker.com.

## Who we are

We are a team of technology lovers trying to provide useful information to the visitors. We write and publish quality articles to help you keep up with the latest technology updates. We publish articles on different categories such as news, reviews, guides, best lists, etc.

Our website address is: [https://thetechhacker.com](https://thetechhacker.com/)

## 1\. What Personal data do we collect?

We collect information from you on various occasions for improving the user experience of our website as well as to serve you with better content. Here are the details of the types of personal data we collect.

### 1.1 Our Services

When you contact us for any services that we provide, we may collect your personal information such as your full name, website name, email address, etc. that you input in the contact form. It is to ensure that we get a basic idea about you to serve you better with your concern. If you wish to remove any of this information from our database, you can contact us and we will clear it for you.

### 1.2 Cookies and Tracking

A cookie is a small text file which is sent to your computer or mobile device by the web server so that the website can remember some information about your browsing activity on the website.  The cookie will collect information relating to your use of our site, information about your device such as the device’s IP address and browser type, demographic data and, if you arrived at our site via a link from third party site, the URL of the linking page. If you are a registered user or subscriber it may also collect your name and email address, which may be transferred to data processors for registered user or subscriber verification purposes. To know more about cookies, [read this article](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie).

We use cookies to track your activities on our website to serve you better. We collect data regarding your sessions using the third-party services like Google Analytics to provide a better user experience on our website. You can read the [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) to know more about their policies. We also use advertising services like Google Adsense which may show ads based on your interests. You can read the [Google ads Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads) to know more about their policies. Also, you may use the Google Analytics [Opt-out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) if you don’t want to send any type of analytics data to Google Analytics.

  * If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.
  * If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.
  * When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.
  * If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### 1.3 Data we Collect from User Inputs

Here is the details of the type of information we collect from the user input fields such as comments, contact forms, email subscriptions, etc. You can get any of these data removed from our website just by emailing us.

 **1.3.1 Comments**

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/>.

After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

 **1.3.2 Email subscription**

When you subscribe to our website, we may collect your personal information such as email address, name, etc. You will receive a confirmation mail to confirm the subscription. You can also opt out of the mailing list any time as you wish just using the link provided in our emails or just by contacting us. We promise to never send you any spam. Please report to us if you receive any. Thetechhacker will never ask for your Credit Card and Bank accounts details, and we request that you do not enter it on our Site.

 **1.3.3 Media**

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website. So, be sure to avoid uploading images with location data.

 **1.3.4 Contact forms**

We keep contact form submissions for an indefinite time period for customer service purposes. If you wish to remove any information you submitted on a contact form on our website, please contact us at pr@thetechhacker.com.

### 1.4 Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### 1.5 Links and Widgets

We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites or services linked to or from Thetechhacker including the information or content contained therein. Our Privacy Policy doesn’t apply to those websites or services. Your interactions with those websites or services are subject to that third party’s own rules and policies. Also, some of the articles may include affiliate links which provide a commission to us.

Also, we use social media widgets such as sharing buttons (Facebook, Twitter, Google+, etc.) to provide the users the chance to share our content, reach our social media accounts, etc. Such services may collect your IP address and the information like which page you are visiting. Your interactions with such features are governed by the privacy policy of the organization providing it.

### 1.6 Server Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this website (like most of the websites on the internet) and any third-party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System logs) use other Personal Data (such as the IP Address) for this purpose. These files log visitors when they visit websites. All hosting companies do this and a part of hosting services’ analytics. The information collected by log files include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), date and time stamp, referring/exit pages, and possibly the number of clicks. These are not linked to any information that is personally identifiable. The purpose of the information is for analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movement on the website, and gathering demographic information. The data will be stored not more than 90 days.

## 2\. What do we use your information for?

Any of the information we collect from you may be used in one of the following ways:

  * To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you).
  * We implement security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you enter, submit, or access your personal information.
  * We use cookies to serve our visitors with personalized advertisements.
  * We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include trusted third parties who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.
  * We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others rights, property, or safety. However, non-personally identifiable visitor information (anonymous usage data, referring/exit pages and URLs, platform types, number of clicks, etc.) may be provided to other parties for tracking, marketing, advertising, or other uses.

## 3\. Who we share your data with

We share some of the information such as comments, session details, cookies, etc. with the following third-party services for the purpose of improving our website, avoiding spam, serving better ads, etc. Below are the details of who we share your data with.

  *  **Analytics services: Google Analytics, Jetpack** : Google Analytics is a web analytics service that helps us to track our visitors and improve the website for the best possible user experience. Google operates independently from our privacy policy and we recommend reading [Google Analytics Privacy and Data Sharing](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245) page to know more about their policies. Also, we use the Jetpack plugin from WordPress that allows us to track the number of visits to our website. You can have a look at the [privacy policy of the Automattic](https://automattic.com/privacy/) to know more.
  *  **Interest-Based Advertising Networks: Adsense** : We use ad service Google Adsense to serve interest-based ads on our website. This third-party advertising service may use the technologies such as Cookies to serve interest-based ads to you. You can read more about the Adsense policies [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads).
  *  **Third-party services like spam filtering: Akismet** : Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service like Akismet that will check your email address, IP, name, comment text, etc. to filter the spam comments. You can read the [Automattic privacy policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/) to know more. We collect information about visitors who comment on Sites that use our Akismet anti-spam service. The information Akismet collect includes the commenter’s IP address, user agent, referrer, and Site URL (along with other information directly provided by the commenter such as their name, username, email address, and the comment itself).

European data protection law requires data about European residents which is transferred outside the European Union to be safeguarded to the same standards as if the data was in Europe. So we always make sure to ensure that these standards are met. We encourage you to read all the Privacy Policies of our third-party service providers to know more about their policies.

## 4\. How long we retain your data

Here is how long we retain personal data collected or processed by the website.

  * If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.
  * The contact form entries will be retained indefinitely until you want us to remove it from our database. This is to ensure that any future communication will be possible and will not create a confusion between us.
  * For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.
  * If you subscribed to our newsletter or services, your data will be retained until you decide to opt out of the mailing list. You can do so by using the unsubscribe link under each mail that we send or by directly contacting us.
  * The Analytics data that we collect will be retained for a period of 90-days by the Google Analytics service. We encourage you to read their privacy policy to know better about it.

## 5\. What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

### 5.1 Children’s Information

Another part of our priority is adding protection for children while using the internet. We encourage parents and guardians to observe, participate in, and/or monitor and guide their online activity.

Thetechhacker does not knowingly collect any Personal Identifiable Information from children under the age of 13. If you think that your child provided this kind of information on our website, we strongly encourage you to contact us immediately and we will do our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## 6\. How we protect your data

We value the privacy of the visitors. So, we are continuously protection your data from any thefts or hacks. We are using the SSL encryption on our website that ensures the website content serves over HTTPS. Also, we have several layers of protection mechanisms in place such as Firewalls, Two-factor authentication, etc. We also train our staff to carefully deal with the user information and never leave any loopholes for any data breach.

### 6.1 What data breach procedures we have in place

We take data privacy seriously. We have internal reporting systems and firewalls that prevent any data breaches by creating an extremely powerful wall between the hackers and our website. We also do have contact mechanism that allows users to reach us and let us know any bugs on our website. We run security inspections on our website to make sure that the website and its data stays protected.

## 7\. Our Contact Information

If you have any doubts regarding our Privacy Policy or want to know something more, you can contact us using our [contact us form](https://thetechhacker.com/contact-us/) or directly send an email to pr@thetechhacker.com. We will get back to you as soon as possible.

## 8\. Changes and Updates to this Policy

We may change the Privacy Policy of Thetechhacker if any changes are needed. So, keep revisiting the page to see if there are any changes to our Privacy Policy. We will also provide the last updated date of this Privacy Policy to let you understand when did the changes happen.

Last Update: 22/05/2018
